Register of the Pia-Maria Starck papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Pia-Maria Starck papers
Bulk, 1967-1990
1948-1995
2004C4
Hoover Institution Archives
71 manuscript boxes (29.6 linear feet)
Correpondence, minutes, reports, studies, bulletins, newsletters, pamphlets, clippings, serial issues, flyers, and leaflets, relating to student and faculty radicalism and other educational issues in West Germany.
Starck, Pia-Maria.
Access
Boxes 65-71 closed until 2025 January 1.
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2004.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Member, Vorstand Hessen, Katholische Elternschaft Deutschlands.
Scope and Content of Collection
The Starck papers represent a wide range of views regarding education reform in West Germany during the 1960s-1980s, represented through a large collection of printed matter published by various political and social advocacy groups. The collection is arranged into three sections: a Subject File, Writings by Others, and Printed Matter.
The Subject File is comprised of a variety of materials collected by Starck on issues related to education reform. These files contain articles, newspaper clippings, and other printed materials, divided by specific topics.
The Writings by Others file is comprised of articles written predominately by German authors on various subjects related to education.
The Printed Matter file makes up the largest section of the collection. It is comprised of German serials, pamphlets, fliers, and other published items related to education. These materials represent a wide spectrum of political and social stances advocated by groups such as the Katholische Elternschaft Deutschlands, the Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands, and the Christlich Demokratische Union among others. This section of the collection also contains a large number of pamphlets, which are arranged according to the organization or political party that published them.
Katholische Elternschaft Deutschlands.; Education--Germany (West); Radicalism--Germany (West); Student movements--Germany (West); Universities and colleges--Germany (West)
- Subject File, 1948-1990
  - Adorno Preis, 1980 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Bundesministerien, 1973-1985 (Box-folder 1: 2-8)
  - Bundesverband der Deutschen Industrie, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Bundesvereinigung der Obenstudiendirektoren, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - Christlich Demokratische Union, 1971-1989 (Box-folder 2: 3 - 6: 6)
  - Deutscher Gewerkschaft, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Deutscher Lehrerverband Hessen, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
  - Deutscher Philologenverband, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 7: 3-4)
  - Förderstufe, 1967-1984 (Box-folder 7: 5 - 8: 4)
  - Frankfurter Schulentwicklungsplan III, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 8: 5 - 9: 5)
  - Frankfurter Schulentwicklungsplan IV, 1981 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Freie Demokratische Partei, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 9: 7-8)
  - Freier Deutscher Autorenverband, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Gemeinnützige Gesellschaft Gesamtschule, 1976-1987 (Box-folder 10: 2-6)
  - Gesamtschule reform, 1967-1986 (Box-folder 11: 1 - 13: 1)
  - Gesellschaft für Humanistische Bildung, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 13: 2)
  - Gesellschaft für Menschenrechte, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 13: 3)
  - Gesellschaft für Verantwortung in der Wissenschaft, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Hanns Seidel Stiftung, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 13: 5-6)
  - Hessen education policies, 1948-1986 (Box-folder 13: 7 - 18: 3)
  - Hessische Eltern Verein, 1971-1989 (Box-folder 18: 4 - 19: 5)
  - Katholische Elternschaft Deutschlands, 1976-1991 (Box-folder 19: 6 - 22: 2)
  - Kölner Interessengemeinschaft, 1972 (Box-folder 22: 3)
  - Landes Eltern Beirat, 1977-1990 (Box-folder 22: 4 - 23: 3)
  - Die Linke, 1973 (Box-folder 23: 4)
  - Medical education, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 23: 5-6)
  - Pedagogy, 1968-1987 (Box 23: 7 - 26: 1)
  - Pre-school education, 1971-1978 (Box-folder 26: 2-3)
  - Religious education, 1967-1985 (Box-folder 26: 4-6)
  - Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands, 1973-1986 (Box-folder 26: 7 - 27: 3)
  - Student protest movements, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 27: 4)
  - Textbooks, 1973-1986 (Box-folder 27: 5 - 28: 6)
  - Verband Bildung und Erziehung, 1982-1988 (Box-folder 28: 7)
  - Verband der Gesichtslehrer Deutschlands, 1987 (Box-folder 28: 8)
  - Verein Katholischer Deutscher Lehrerinnen, 1976 (Box-folder 28: 9)
  - Volksbegehren, 1973-1987 (Box-folder 28: 10 - 30: 4)
  - Wirtschaftsakademie für Lehrer, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 30: 5-6)
- Writings by Others, 1958-1991
  - Affemann, Rudolf, 1976 (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - Amthauer, Rudolf, 1976 (Box-folder 30: 8)
  - Andersen, Bo Dan, Soren Hansen and Jesper Jensen, 1969 (Box-folder 63: 29)
  - Aurin, Kurt, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 30: 9)
  - Barthold, Werner, undated (Box-folder 30: 10)
  - Bartsch, Günter, 1971 (Box-folder 63: 30)
  - Bauer, undated (Box-folder 30: 11)
  - Bauer, Dietmar, undated (Box-folder 30: 12)
  - Bauer, K.O., 1977 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Baumann, Gerhard, 1972 (Box-folder 31: 2)
  - Beck, Gertrude, 1972 (Box-folder 31: 3)
  - Berchem, 1979 (Box-folder 31: 4)
  - Brezinka, Wolfgang, circa 1970-1980 (Box-folder 31: 5, Box-folder 51: 1)
  - Buber-Neumann, Margarete, 1971 (Box-folder 31: 6)
  - Carstens, Karl, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 31: 7, Box-folder 63: 1)
  - Dahrendorf, Ralf, 1976 (Box-folder 31: 8)
  - Deschner, Günther, 1973 (Box-folder 31: 9)
  - Ebert, Wilhelm, 1979 (Box-folder 31: 10)
  - Eick, Wilfried, 1971 (Box-folder 31: 11)
  - von Eiff, August Wilhelm, circa 1980-1990 (Box-folder 63: 32)
  - Eisert, Walter, 1973 (Box-folder 31: 12)
  - Engels, circa 1970-1980 (Box-folder 31: 13)
  - Erdsieck, Gerhard, 1969 (Box-folder 31: 14)
  - Frisch, Max, 1970 (Box-folder 31: 15)
  - Gaede, Jürgen, 1976 (Box-folder 31: 16)
  - Geissler, Heiner, 1978 (Box-folder 51: 2)
  - Graßmann, Siegfried, 1978 (Box-folder 31: 17)
  - Grille, Dietrich, 1975 (Box-folder 31: 18)
  - Grisart, Albert, 1966 (Box-folder 31: 19)
  - Grosser, Dietrich, 1976 (Box-folder 31: 20)
  - Günther, Henning and Rudolf Willeke, 1982 (Box-folder 63: 33)
  - Hahn, 1974 (Box-folder 31: 21)
  - Härtle, Heinrich, 1971 (Box-folder 31: 22)
  - Heckenhausen, Heinz, 1972 (Box-folder 31: 23, Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Heereman, Michaela, 1988 (Box-folder 63: 34)
  - Heesen, Peter, 1986 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - Hegelheimer, Armin, undated (Box-folder 32: 3, Box-folder 63: 35)
  - Hempfer, Klaus W., 1991 (Box-folder 32: 4)
  - Hennis, Wilhelm, 1970 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - Hitpass, Josef, 1965-1983 (Box-folder 63: 36-38, Box-folder 32: 6-7)
  - Holthoff, Fritz, 1975 (Box-folder 32: 8)
  - Hövels, O., undated (Box-folder 32: 9)
  - Ilkenhaus, Helmut, undated (Box-folder 32: 10)
  - Jäger, Wolfgang, 1961 (Box-folder 32: 11)
  - Jochimsen, Reimut, 1968 (Box-folder 32: 12)
  - Kasper, Helmut, circa 1970s (Box-folder 32: 13)
  - Kempf, Wilhelm, Bishop, 1963 (Box-folder 63: 39)
  - Kern, Erich, 1971 (Box-folder 32: 14)
  - Kleinschmidt, G., 1976 (Box-folder 32: 15)
  - Klett, Michael, 1973 (Box-folder 32: 16)
  - Knapp, Horst, 1971 (Box-folder 32: 17)
  - Koplin, Raimund, 1968 (Box-folder 63: 40)
  - Krefeld, Heinrich, 1967 (Box-folder 32: 18)
  - Lempp, Reinhart, 1979 (Box-folder 32: 19)
  - Lobkowicz, Nikolaus, 1978 (Box-folder 32: 20)
  - Lübbe Hermann, 1973-1986, undated (Box-folder 63: 41-42, Box-folder 33: 1)
  - Maier, 1977 (Box-folder 33: 2)
  - Maier, Hans and Michael Zöller, 1970 (Box-folder 51: 3)
  - Mayer-Vorfelder, Gerhard, 1981 (Box-folder 33: 3)
  - Meany, George, 1974 (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - Migdahl, Uhlrike, 1982 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  - Müller, Helmut, 1971 (Box-folder 33: 6)
  - Müller-Haccius, Otto, undated (Box-folder 33: 7)
  - Münch, Werner, 1976 (Box-folder 63: 43)
  - Nebel, Franz, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 8)
  - Neugebauer, H., 1972 (Box-folder 33: 9)
  - Neumann, 1978 (Box-folder 33: 10)
  - Nipperday, Thomas, undated (Box-folder 33: 11)
  - Noelle-Neumann, E., 1975 (Box-folder 33: 12)
  - Nolte, Ernst, 1971 (Box-folder 51: 4)
  - Ortlieb, Heinz-Dietrich, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 63: 44, Box-folder 33: 13)
  - Piltz, Hans-Hermann, 1980 (Box-folder 33: 14)
  - Poser, Günter, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 15)
  - Poth, Hugo, undated (Box-folder 33: 16)
  - Presbesch, Rudolf, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 17)
  - Püttner, Günter, 1979 (Box-folder 33: 18)
  - Rädel, Fritz E., 1978 (Box-folder 63: 45)
  - Radtke, undated (Box-folder 33: 19)
  - Ratzinger, Joseph, Cardinal, 1984 (Box-folder 63: 46)
  - Rauschenberger, Hans, 1977 (Box-folder 33: 20)
  - Rauscher, Anton, 1973 (Box-folder 63: 47)
  - Rock, 1975 (Box-folder 33: 21)
  - Rogalla von Bieberstein, Johannes, 1976 (Box-folder 63: 48)
  - Rüegg, Walter, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 33: 22, Box-folder 63: 49-51)
  - Scheffer, Hans Heinrich, undated (Box-folder 33: 23)
  - Schiller, Joachim, 1970 (Box-folder 33: 24)
  - Schmidt, Hatto H., 1974-1977 (Box-folder 63: 52, Box-folder 51: 5)
  - Schoeck, Helmut, 1971 (Box-folder 51: 6)
  - Simmel, Oskar, 1958 (Box-folder 63: 53)
  - Spaemann, Robert, undated (Box-folder 33: 25)
  - Steinbuch, Karl, 1973 (Box-folder 33: 26)
  - Stingl, Josef, 1979 (Box-folder 33: 27)
  - Stoltenberg, Gerhard, 1966 (Box-folder 64: 12, Box-folder 63: 54)
  - Stöklein, Paul, 1972-1989 (Box-folder 33: 28)
  - Strauß, Franz Josef, 1971 (Box-folder 33: 29)
  - Stuckmann, Elmar, 1975-1980 (Box-folder 33: 30)
  - Süllwold, L., undated (Box-folder 33: 31)
  - Thieme, Werner, 1970 (Box-folder 64: 13)
  - Thomas, Bernd W., 1980 (Box-folder 34: 1)
  - Tormin, Walter, 1960 (Box-folder 34: 2)
  - von Uexküll, Th., 1967 (Box-folder 64: 14)
  - Walderdorff, Graf, 1972 (Box-folder 34: 3)
  - Watrin, Christian, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 64: 15-19, Box-folder 34: 4)
  - Wichmann, Jochen, 1973 (Box-folder 34: 5)
  - Wittmann, Waldemar, 1973 (Box-folder 34: 6)
  - Weber, Werner, 1969 (Box-folder 34: 7)
  - Wenderoth, Gerhard, 1977 (Box-folder 64: 20)
  - Wolf, Ernst, undated (Box-folder 34: 8)
  - Zipfel, Friedrich, 1962 (Box-folder 34: 9)
- Printed Matter, 1961-1995
  - "Aktionsprogramm zum Kampf gegen Abbau demokratischer Rechte in Schule und Hochschule,", undated (Box-folder 34: 10)
  - Analysen, 1972 (Box-folder 34: 11)
  - Anleitung zum Handeln, 1964 (Box-folder 52: 1)
  - Arbeitsbuch für den Sachunterricht in der Grundschule Lehrerverband I, 1973 (Box-folder 34: 12-15)
  - Argumente zu Wirtschafts-fragen, 1978 (Box-folder 52: 2)
  - Aspekte, 1972 (Box-folder 34: 16)
  - Aste-Info, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 34: 17)
  - Beiträge zum Jugendschutz, 1961 (Box-folder 52: 3)
  - Beiträge zur Deutschland-politik, 1985 (Box-folder 52: 4)
  - Beiträge zur Gesellschafts- und Bildungspolitik Institut der deutschen Wirtschaft, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 52: 5-7)
  - Beratung in der Schule, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 35: 1-4)
  - Bildung Aktuell, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 52: 8-10)
  - Blickpunkt Schule, 1980-1988 (Box-folder 52: 11-69, Box-folder 53: 1-6)
  - Concepte: Magazin für Sozialethik und Sozialhygiene, 1975 (Box-folder 35: 5)
  - Das Deutsche Bildungsmagazin, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 35: 6)
  - Deutsche Lehrer Zeitung, 1973 (Box-folder 35: 7)
  - Die Detusche Schule, 1975 (Box-folder 53: 7)
  - "Deutscher Bildungsrat: Empfehlungen der Bildungskommission,", 1969 (Box-folder 53: 8)
  - Deutscher Juristentag, 1976-1981 (Box-folder 53: 9-11)
  - Deutschland Magazin, 1969-1980 (Box-folder 36: 1 - 37: 6)
  - "Dieser Landeseltern Beirat vertritt nicht Mehrheitinteressen: Eine ideologiekritische Betrachtung,", 1982 (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - "Differenzierung Freie Arbeit,", 1978 (Box-folder 37: 8)
  - Diskus, 1971-1980 (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - "Die DKP Hessen zu den Rahmenrichtlinien,", undated (Box-folder 38: 2)
  - Echo & Hall, undated (Box-folder 38: 3)
  - "Einladung zum Theatertreffen,", undated (Box 38: 4)
  - Eltern Forum, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 38: 5-9)
  - Eltern, Schulen, Erzieher, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 39: 1-3)
  - Elternblatt, 1971 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Elternbrief, 1972-1995 (Box-folder 39: 5-7, Box-folder 40: 1-3)
  - "Energie und ihre Anwendung in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland,", 1979 (Box 40: 4)
  - Entwurf für das schul- und bildungspolitische Programm der DKP, 1985 (Box-folder 53: 12-13)
  - Erziehung und Klassenkampf, 1975 (Box-folder 53: 14)
  - Erziehung und Wissenschaft, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 40: 5-6)
  - Essentials, circa 1970s (Box-folder 53: 15)
  - Der Evangelische Erzieher, 1969 (Box-folder 53: 16)
  - FACIT, circa 1970s (Box-folder 53: 17)
  - Der Föhn, 1973 (Box-folder 40: 7)
  - Forum E, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 40: 8)
  - Fragen der Freiheit, 1978 (Box-folder 53: 18)
  - Frankfurter Allgemeine Zeitung, 1973 (Box-folder 53: 19)
  - Frankfurter Lehrerblatt, 1971 (Box-folder 53: 20)
  - Gazette Bienenkorb, 1969 (Box-folder 40: 9)
  - "Gemeinsam lernen in Deutschunterricht,", 1980 (Box-folder 40: 10)
  - Geschichte Politik und ihre Didaktik, 1993 (Box-folder 53: 21)
  - "Gewerkscahft Erziehung und Wissenscahft Information und Stellungnahme,", 1973-1974 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Das Gymnasium in Rheinland-Pfalz, 1979-1989 (Box-folder 41: 2-5)
  - Häuserratszeitung, 1974 (Box-folder 41: 6)
  - Hessen, 1974 (Box-folder 53: 22)
  - Hessenforum, 1974 (Box-folder 53: 23)
  - Hessische Kultusminister, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 64: 2-11, Box-folder 62: 1-5)
  - Hessische Lehrerzeitung, 1973-1981 (Box-folder 41: 7-9)
  - "Historisches Museum Frankfurt: Historische Dokumenten 19. Jahrhundert,", 1975 (Box-folder 42: 1)
  - Die Höhere Schule, 1970-1990 (Box-folder 42: 2 - 44: 2)
  - Hornisse, 1972 (Box-folder 44: 3)
  - Humanismus und Politik, 1983 (Box-folder 53: 24-25)
  - "i,", 1969 (Box-folder 44: 4)
  - IAP Dienst, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 44: 5)
  - ibw Journal, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 53: 26-36, Box-folder 44: 7-10)
  - Im Brennpunkt, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 44: 6)
  - Info Dienst, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 45: 1 - 46: 3)
  - Informationsdienst Arbeiterbildung, 1972 (Box-folder 53: 37)
  - Informationsdienst des Sozialistischen Lehrerbundes, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 46: 4, Box-folder 53: 38, Box-folder 54: 1-10)
  - Der Informationskreis Kernenergie, 1979 (Box-folder 46: 5)
  - Intern Informationen, 1972 (Box-folder 46: 6)
  - Internationales Gewerbearchiv, 1975 (Box-folder 54: 11)
  - IW Dienst, 1987 (Box-folder 46: 7)
  - "Jahresberichte 1972-1975, Fürst-Johann-Ludwig Schule Gesamtschule," (Box-folder 46: 8)
  - Katholische Bildung, 1979-1984 (Box-folder 54: 12-21)
  - Kirche und Gesellschaft, 1974-1988 (Box-folder 54: 24-30)
  - Kommunistische Erziehung, circa 1960s (Box-folder 54: 31)
  - Kommunistische Hochschulezeitung des KSV Frankfurt, 1972 (Box-folder 46: 9)
  - Konstanzer Blätter für Hochschulfragen, 1966 (Box-folder 54: 32)
  - Kontakt-Studium, 1971 (Box-folder 46: 10)
  - Kontrast, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 46: 11)
  - KSG Programm, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 54: 22-23)
  - Kürbiskern, 1974 (Box-folder 54: 33)
  - Lebendiges Gymnasium, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 54: 34-35)
  - Lehrer und Schule, 1986 (Box-folder 54: 36)
  - Leistungsmessung in Gesamtschule, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 46: 12)
  - Lesen, Darstellen, Begreifen, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 54: 37)
  - Links, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 47: 1)
  - Marxistische Blätter, 1964 (Box-folder 54: 38)
  - "Materialen zur anti militarischen Friedensarbeit,", 1974 (Box-folder 47: 2)
  - "Materialen zur Lehrerausbildung,", 1971 (Box-folder 47: 3)
  - "Materialen zum Unterricht,", 1980 (Box-folder 47: 4)
  - "Materialen zur Unterrichtspraxis,", 1973 (Box-folder 54: 39-40)
  - Medien-Sexual-Pädegogik, 1974 (Box-folder 47: 5)
  - Mitteilungen: Erzdiözese Paderborn, 1974 (Box-folder 54: 41)
  - Mitteilungen: Industrie- und Handelskammer Frankfurt am Main, 1973 (Box-folder 47: 6)
  - Mitteilungen: Philologenverband Rheinland-Pfalz, 1974 (Box-folder 55: 1-4, Box-folder 54: 42-51)
  - Mitteilungensblatt, 1970-1979 (Box-folder 55: 5-13)
  - Moment Mal, 1971 (Box-folder 47: 7)
  - Neue Christlich Demokratische Politik, 1972 (Box-folder 55: 14)
  - Die neue Linke, 1971-1979 (Box-folder 55: 15-52)
  - Neue Technologien in Bildung und Schule, 1985 (Box-folder 55: 53)
  - "Ordungsprinzipen der Verfassung des Grundgesetzes,", undated (Box-folder 47: 8)
  - Ost Kurier, 1972 (Box-folder 47: 9)
  - Päd. Extra, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 47: 10)
  - Pädagogik und freie Schule, 1973-1994 (Box-folder 56: 1-13, Box-folder 55: 54-79)
  - Pen, 1968 (Box-folder 47: 11)
  - Pharma Dialog, 1973 (Box-folder 47: 12)
  - Probleme der Humanistische Bildung, 1965 (Box-folder 56: 14-15)
  - Probleme des Friedens und des Sozialismus, 1971 (Box-folder 56: 16)
  - "Protokoll einer Besprechung zwischen den Unterzeichnern des offenen Briefes von 15.12.1971 unter den Sonder-Kommission des Akademischen Senats," (Box-folder 47: 13)
  - Radikal Info, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 47: 14)
  - 'ran, 1974 (Box-folder 47: 15)
  - Reform Universität oder Kader Hochschule, 1970 (Box-folder 56: 17)
  - Reihe Roter Pauker, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 56: 18-23)
  - Revolutionäre Bücher, 1978 (Box-folder 56: 24)
  - Rote Presse Korrespondenz, 1971 (Box-folder 47: 16)
  - Rote Schülerpresse, 1971 (Box-folder 47: 17)
  - Rotes Banner, 1971 (Box-folder 47: 18)
  - Rumpelstilzchen, 1974 (Box-folder 47: 19)
  - Schul Report, 1973-1988 (Box-folder 48: 1 - 49: 2)
  - Schulbuch Forum, 1977 (Box-folder 49: 3)
  - Schulbuchkritiken, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 56: 25-26)
  - Schule Heute, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 56: 27-28)
  - Schule im Blickpunkt, 1977 (Box-folder 56: 29)
  - "Schule zwischen Förderung und Auslese,", 1979 (Box-folder 49: 4)
  - Schuleversuche mit Gesamtschulen in Bayern, 1977 (Box-folder 56: 30)
  - Schüler Info, circa 1980s (Box-folder 49: 5)
  - Schüler Vertretung, 1975 (Box-folder 49: 6)
  - Schülerzeitung, circa 1980s (Box-folder 49: 7)
  - Sectio: Information für Medizin- Studenten und Assistenten, 1972 (Box-folder 49: 8)
  - Sehen, Beurteilen, Handeln, 1971 (Box-folder 49: 9)
  - "Sicher ist Ihnen schon aufgefallen, dass...,", circa 1970-1980 (Box-folder 49: 10)
  - Sozialistische Modelle, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 56: 31-35)
  - Standpunkte der schulischen Erziehung, 1980 (Box-folder 56: 36-37)
  - "Strafvollzug heute,", 1972 (Box-folder 49: 11)
  - Student, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 56: 38-40)
  - Student protest fliers, 1967-1975 (Box-folder 49: 12 - 50: 4)
  - "Studie zur Situation an den Hochschulen in der Bundesrepublik Deutschland nach Einführung unterschielicher Landeshochschulgesetz aufgezeigt am Beispiel der Chemie,", undated (Box-folder 50: 5)
  - "Das süße Gift der rote Lehrer,", 1974 (Box-folder 50: 6)
  - Thesen zur Technologie, circa 1980-1990 (Box-folder 50: 7)
  - Tops: Eine Mainzer Studentenzeitung, 1971 (Box-folder 50: 8)
  - Underground, 1970 (Box-folder 50: 9)
  - Uni hh, 1972 (Box-folder 50: 10)
  - VDR Informiert, 1979 (Box-folder 56: 41)
  - "Verkehrsrechts- und Verkersaufklärungsheft,", circa 1960s (Box-folder 50: 11)
  - Vertrauliche Mitteilungen aus Politik und Wirtschaft, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 50: 12)
  - "Vom Verfall des humanistischen Gymnasiums,", 1972 (Box-folder 50: 13)
  - Vorn, 1973 (Box-folder 50: 14)
  - "Wahl RCDS,", 1973 (Box-folder 50: 15)
  - Wahlzeitung der kommunistischen Studentengruppe (Marxisten-Leninisten), circa 1970s (Box-folder 50: 16)
  - "Der Wahrheit auf der Spur Fall Bischofsheim: Verwirrung um Gesamtschul Sozialarbeiter,", 1977 (Box-folder 56: 42)
  - "Was wollen Wir? Auszug aus dem Programm der nationalsozialistischen Detuschen Arbeiterpartei,", undated (Box-folder 50: 17)
  - Die Wende, circa 1970s (Box-folder 50: 18)
  - "Wirtschaft in der Verantwortung für die Zukunft,", 1979 (Box-folder 50: 19)
  - Wirtschaft und Wissenschaft, 1976 (Box-folder 50: 20)
  - "Wissenschaftliche Pädagogik,", 1987 (Box-folder 56: 43)
  - Zeitbühne, 1972-1979 (Box-folder 56: 44-54, Box-folder 58: 1-37)
  - "Zum Nachdenken,", 1971 (Box-folder 58: 38)
  - "Zur lage von Forschung, Lehre und Studium an den Hochschulen der Bundesrepublik Deutschland,", 1971 (Box-folder 58: 39)
  - Pamphlets, 1965-1993
    Scope and Contents note
    Consists of pamphlets related to West German education. Arranged in alphabetical order by the name of the publishing organization.
    - General pedagogy, 1974-1975, circa 1970s (Box-folder 58: 40-42)
    - Amt für staatsbürgerliche Bildung in Schleswig-Holstein, 1973 (Box-folder 58: 43)
    - Arbeitgeverband der hessischen Metallindustrie e.V., 1981 (Box-folder 58: 44)
    - Arbeitsgemeinschaft der zwölf hessischen Industrie - und Handelskammern, 1977 (Box-folder 58: 45)
    - Arbeitsgemeinschaft für katholische Familienbildung, 1977 (Box-folder 58: 46)
    - Arbeitskreis Grundschule e.V., 1975 (Box-folder 59: 1-2)
    - Bayerische Staatsminister für Unterricht und Kultus, 1975 (Box-folder 59: 3)
    - Bergerdorfer Gesprächskreis, 1987 (Box-folder 64: 1)
    - Bundeselternrat, circa 1970s (Box-folder 59: 4)
    - Bundesverband der Deutschen Industrie e.V., 1980-1982 (Box-folder 59: 5-6)
    - Bundesvereinigung der Deutschen Arbeitgebeverbände, 1974-1987 (Box-folder 59: 7-11)
    - Bürgeraktion freie Schulwahl, 1984 (Box-folder 59: 12-14)
    - Christian-Albrechts-Universität, 1967 (Box-folder 59: 15)
    - Christlich Demokratische Union, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 59: 16-42)
    - Deutsche Bischofskonferenz, 1977 (Box-folder 59: 43)
    - Deutscher Bundestag, 1972 (Box-folder 59: 44)
    - Deutscher Elternverein, 1979 (Box-folder 59: 45-49)
    - Deutscher Gewerkschaftsbund, 1979 (Box-folder 59: 50)
    - Deutscher Lehrerverband Hamburg, 1976 (Box-folder 59: 51-52)
    - Deutscher Philologenverband, 1965-1983 (Box-folder 59: 53-55)
    - Elternverein Nordrhein-Westfalen, 1980 (Box-folder 60: 1)
    - Evangelischen Kirche in Deutschland, 1978 (Box-folder 60: 2-3)
    - Fraunhofer-Institut für Atmosphärische Umweltforschung Garmisch-Partenkirchen, 1979 (Box-folder 60: 4)
    - Friedenschule, 1979 (Box-folder 60: 5)
    - Gesamtverband der Lehrer an Beruflichen Schulen in Hessen e.V., 1979 (Box-folder 60: 6-7)
    - Gesellschaft Erziehung und Wissenschaft, 1971 (Box-folder 60: 8)
    - Gewerkschaft Erziehung und Wissenschaft, circa 1970-1980 (Box-folder 60: 9-15)
    - Gewerkschaftliche Vertrauensleute für eine Antikapitalistische Betriebsstrategie, 1972 (Box-folder 60: 16)
    - Hanns-Seidel-Stiftung, 1975-1984 (Box-folder 60: 17-45)
    - Hermann-Ethlers-Akademie, 1982 (Box-folder 60: 46)
    - Hessische Elternverein, 1973-1982 (Box-folder 61: 1-20, Box-folder 60: 47-48)
    - Hessische Kultusminister, 1968-1987 (Box-folder 61: 21-47)
    - Hessische Stiftung Friedens- und Konfliktsforschung, 1975 (Box-folder 62: 6)
    - Hessischer Philologenverband, 1969-1982 (Box-folder 62: 7-10)
    - Hessisches Institut für Bildungsplanung und Schulentwicklung, 1977 (Box-folder 62: 11)
    - International Council on the Future of the University, 1977 (Box-folder 62: 12)
    - Johann Wolfgang Goethe-Universität, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 62: 13-15)
    - Junge Union Hessen, circa 1970-1980 (Box-folder 62: 16)
    - Katholische Elternschaft Deutschlands, 1980-1993 (Box-folder 62: 17-40)
    - Katholische Elternschaft Sauerland, 1982 (Box-folder 62: 41)
    - Katholische Erziehergemeinschaft in Bayern, circa 1970-1980 (Box-folder 62: 42)
    - Kulturpolitik der Länder, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 62: 43)